Samia Maguedouda BELHADDAD

Currently pursuing a 2 years master's degree program in Applied Statistics & Probabilities +2 years of learning and experiencing with Machine Learning & Data Science tools & methodologies. Aiming to combine my Academic Background and my self-taught skills to solve practical problems

m.samia.belhaddad@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/samiabelhaddad

https://github.com/Hypatchia/

+213541325492

Algiers, Algeria

Education

Master's in Applied Statistics and Probability: First Year

University of Science and Technology Houari Boumediene

2021 - 2022

- Time Series Theory & Analysis

- Stochastic Modeling & Simulation

- Parametric Statistics & Estimation

- Measure Theory & Stochastic Calculus - Information Theory

Queuing Theory

- Regression & Classification Analysis

- Non Parametric Statistical Testing

Inferential Statistics

Introduction to Economy

Bachelor's Degree in Mathematics

University of Science and Technology Houari Boumediene

2018 - 2021

- Algorithms & Data Structures

- Linear Algebra

- Real Analysis , Complex Analysis

- Mathmatical Logic

- Functional Analysis & Hilbert Spaces - First Order Differential Equations

- Multivariate Analysis

- Abstract Algebra, Fields & Ring theory

- Numerical Analysis

- C Programming

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Data Scientist (Fall 2021 Internship)

- -Time Series Analysis of agricultural historical data coming from sensor devices
- -Explored state of the art deep learning models for forecasting

-Performed Data analysis and modeling using LSTMs Data Science Content Creator (Summer 2021 Internship)

-Built End-to-End Data Science guided learning projects in regression and image classification

Content and Community Manager (2020-2021)

Wejehni 🗗

- -We helped thousands of students answering their concerns about higher education.
- -Created social media content about education & university programs in Algeria.
- -Managed to respond to career concerns of hundreds of high school students

Web Content Creator (08-10/2019)

- -Acquired knowledge about Business, Marketing, Entrepreneurship, Startups .
- -Worked on Mapping the Algerian Entrepreneurship Ecosystem Project.
- -Gained skills in content management systems (WordPress).

VOLUNTEER WORKS

Event Organizer: CSE:Club Scientifique de l'ESI (2017 - 2020) 🗷

Participated in the organization of several events during +2 years of active Membership including the Largest Hackathon in Africa and HacklTin Algeria

Raising awareness about Mental Health Topics in the Algerian Society through Events and a Digital Presence & social media content

Social Media Manager: Algeria Game Challenge (07/2019)

Algeria Game Challenge is the first and the largest Game Development competition in Algeria I was in charge of the Facebook page of the competition. Created Visuals and posts featuring the event.

Coding Mentor for Kids: Kids Can Code (02/2019)

An event by the club C&S, in which students in IT teach kids programming using Scratch

INTERESTS

- Traveling
- Sustainability
- Behavioral Psychology
- Learning

Technical Skills

- Languages: Python, R
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Machine Learning Algorithms
- Data Science Libraries: Scikit-Learn, Numpy, Pandas, Seaborn...
- Deep Learning Architectures: NNs,CNNs, RNNs,GNNs
- Deep Learning Frameworks: Tensorflow -Keras
- Google Al Platform
- Machine Learning Pipelines: Tensorflow Extended
- Git ,Github , Gitlab
- Databases
- SQL

Soft Skills

- Autonomy
- Research
- Adaptability
- Communication
- Problem Solving Presentation

PROJECTS AND RESEARCH

- The objective was to detect whether a manufactured product is defected or not
- Performed Image Classification using CNNS and Tensorflow Sequential API
- Trained a Deep Learning model for Binary and Multiclass Classification

App Enrollment Prediction (08/2021) ☑

- Predict App Enrollement based on User interaction Data: Costumer Behavior
- Trained a Logistic Regression Model on a real life Dataset
- Achieved 85 % measure of Separability

An overview of Homomorphic Encryption (04/2021-07/2021) ♂

- Analysed state of the art abstractions of Finite fields and Ring Cryptography
- Explored the applications of Homomorphic Encryption in the current era
- Focued on highlighting the Paillier Cryptosystem

Clustering Townships of Algiers based on Venues (05/2020-06/2020) ☑

- Applied Data Science Methodology from Business understanding to attainting business objective
- Used Location Data and FoursquareAPI
- Trained a Kmeans Clustering model to group townships based on Target Venues
- Performed using Pandas, numpy, Matplotlib, ScikitLearn, Seaborn ...

CERTIFICATES AND COURSES

- Machine Learning Engineering for production Specialization (2022) ♂
- DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer Specialization (08/2021) ☑
- Software Engineering for Data Scientists in Python (01/2021) ☑
- IBM Data Science Specialization (07/2020)

 ☑
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning (07/2020)

 ☑ □
- Introduction to Psychology (07/2020) ☑
- Data Analysis Track from Udacity (05/2020) ♂

LANGUAGES

English Full Professional Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

Arabic

Native or Bilingual Proficiency